Hello everyone! Today I'm excited to show you Historical Traces
An innovative Multi-Agent system for script creation
In just a few minutes, you'll see how 5 specialized AI agents
work together to create a complete, theater-ready script
Let's dive in with a classic Chinese poem theme:
"The Peach Blossom Spring"
First, I've already started the system
Opening the browser at localhost:8700
Here's our workspace interface
On the left, you can see 6 channels
The general channel is our main interface
where we interact with the system
Behind the scenes, we have 5 specialized agents:
AgentG - The Coordinator, our single point of contact
AgentA - The Historian, collects historical research
AgentB - The Script Planner, designs the story structure
AgentC - The Interactive Performer, engages users in creative decisions
AgentD - The Script Writer, produces the final professional script
Now, let me input our theme in the general channel:
"Theme: The Peach Blossom Spring"
Watch what happens... AgentG immediately responds:
"Theme received, AgentA is collecting historical data"
AgentA, our historian, springs into action
It's gathering comprehensive historical background
Including Tao Yuanming's biography from Eastern Jin Dynasty
The historical context of 421 AD
Social turmoil and escapism themes
Literary analysis and cultural significance
And there we go! AgentA has published
a comprehensive 1,200-word historical research package
You can see details about the poet, the era
and the meaning behind this utopian story
Now AgentB, our script planner, takes over
Based on the historical research
It's designing a three-act structure:
Act 1 - Fisherman discovers the hidden valley
Act 2 - Interactions with the utopian villagers
Act 3 - Departure and the failed return
AgentB has also created character profiles
mapped out the emotional arcs
And identified key dramatic moments
This outline is now ready for the interactive phase
Here's where it gets interesting
The interactive phase with AgentC!
AgentC splits the outline into 5 scenes
and asks me to make creative decisions for each one
Scene 1 appears:
"The fisherman travels along the stream, seeing peach blossoms..."
Question: How should we portray the fisherman's feelings?
I'll choose option B - attracted by the beauty, decides to explore
Watch what happens... AgentC receives my choice
and immediately presents Scene 2
"The fisherman discovers a narrow opening
He enters and finds a whole new world..."
This continues for 5 rounds total
Each choice shapes the final script
Notice how AgentC waits for my response before continuing
This is our innovative 4-layer filtering mechanism
It ensures strict "one question, one answer" flow
preventing the agent from auto-advancing
I'll quickly complete the remaining rounds...
Making choices that shape the narrative
After the 5th interaction
AgentD - our script writer - finally speaks!
Throughout the entire process
AgentD has been silently collecting everything
The historical research from AgentA
The three-act structure from AgentB
And all 5 of my creative decisions
Now it integrates all this information
Into a complete, professional script
And here it is! A 2,600-word theater script
Including character list with detailed profiles
Scene descriptions and stage directions
Dialogue for all characters
Psychological descriptions and emotional cues
Stage lighting and blocking notes
This is production-ready
So what makes this system special
from a technical perspective?
First: Strict Agent Specialization
Each of the 5 agents has a clear role
And only subscribes to necessary channels
This channel isolation reduces token consumption by over 50%
Second: State Machine Control
AgentC implements a 4-layer filtering system
Content validation, Source verification
Marker detection, State consistency check
This ensures AgentC never advances without user input
Solving a common Multi-Agent challenge
Third: Silent Collection Pattern
AgentD observes the entire process without interrupting
Then delivers one high-quality final output
More efficient than constant back-and-forth
Fourth: Central Coordinator Architecture
AgentG acts as a hub
Managing all task distribution and result aggregation
Users only interact with one channel - simple and clean
These innovations bring token usage
from 500,000+ down to 200,000-300,000 per session
So that's Historical Traces
A Multi-Agent system for collaborative script creation
Use cases include: Education - Students experience history interactively
Creative Writing - Rapid professional script generation
And Cultural Industry - Content for film, theater, and documentaries
The entire codebase is open-source on GitHub
Check out the link in the description!
Thanks for watching, and I hope you enjoyed seeing OpenAgents in action!